openpli.org 2019-11-17

# Privacy Policy | OpenPLi - Open Source Set-Top Box Software

We, “Vereniging PLi”, only use personal data you have given us, and only to provide our services to you. We have described how we collect, store and use your data in this Privacy Policy. We take seriously our responsibilities to look after your data and we are committed to protecting your privacy. There are steps you can take to control what we do with your data and we have explained those steps in this Privacy Policy.

When we talk about data and personal data in this Privacy Policy, we mean personal data which identify you or which could be used to identify you such as your name and contact details. It may also include information about how you use our websites.

### Who is responsible for your data

“ **Vereniging PLi** ” is responsible for your data. We are registered as association with full legal rights (“Vereniging met volledige rechtsbevoegdheid”), registered with the Dutch Chamber of Commerce (“KvK”)  under **company  number 09182341**. We are the data controller of the data which we collect from you, and as such we control the ways your personal data are collected and the purposes for which your personal data are used.

### Personal data we collect about you

Depending on how you use our services and our websites, we might collect the following kinds of information about you:

Your name and contact details 

(email address, desired username, optionally fullname and date of birth)

| When you create an account with us  
---|---  
Your Gender, Location, Country and interests | When you enter those on your profile page  
Any other personal data you share | When you create posts on our forum website  
Communication we have with you 

(emails, letters, telephone calls, messages to our online chat service, messages sent to us through our social media platforms, feedback)

| When you get in touch with us  
When you respond to our requests for feedback  
Information about you, your location and how you use our websites | When you use our digital systems and services  
When you accept our cookies placed on your device  
When you update your account information  
When you click on our banner adverts  
When you fill in forms on our website  
When you get in touch with us  
When you respond to our requests for feedback  
When you opt in to receiving messages from us  
  
Note that our forums are accessable to the public, and can be accessed anonymously. As such, any data you post in the forum will become part of the public domain, and is therefore not covered under “personal data”.

We can only use your personal data if we have a proper reason for doing so. According to the law, we can only use your data for one or more of these reasons:

  *     * If we have a legal duty to use your data for a particular reason, or

  * When you consent to it, or
  * When it is in our legitimate interests.

Legitimate interests are our business reasons for using your data, but even so, we will not unfairly put our legitimate interests above what is best for you.

In the table below, we have set out the different ways in which we use your personal data and the reasons we rely on for using that data.

If we rely on our legitimate interests for using your personal data, we will explain that to you.

What we use your personal data for | Legal grounds for using it | Our legitimate interests  
---|---|---  
  
  * To provide services to you
  * Communicating with you and to send you information

| 

  * Our legitimate interests
  * With your consent

| 

  * Keeping our records up to date
  * Developing products and services
  * Being efficient about how we provide our services and fulfil our legal duties

  * To communicate with you and manage our relationship with you
  * To personalise and improve your customer experience
  * To inform you about our news and offers that we think you might be interested in

| 

  * Our legitimate interests
  * With your consent

| 

  * Keeping our records up to date, working out which of our products and services may interest you
  * Developing products and services
  * Being efficient about how we provide our services and fulfil our legal duties

  * To obey laws and regulations which apply to us and the way we deliver our services
  * To respond to complaints and to seek to resolve them

| 

  * Our legitimate interests
  * Our legal duty
  * With your consent

| 

  * Being efficient about how we provide our services and fulfil our legal duties
  * Identifying ways to improve the way we deliver services to our users

  * To run our association in an efficient and proper way
  * To fulfil our administrative purposes including accounting, billing and audit
  * To improve our services
  * To manage how we work with other companies that provide services to us and our users
  * To protect our interests

| 

  * Our legitimate interests
  * Our legal duty

| 

  * Being efficient about how we provide our services and fulfil our legal duties
  * Identifying ways to improve the way we deliver services to our users

  * To develop and manage our brand, products and services
  * To test new products and services

| 

  * Our legitimate interests
  * Our legal duty

| 

  * Being efficient about how we provide our services and fulfil our legal duties
  * Identifying ways to improve the way we deliver services to our users

We keep your data only for as long as we need it. How long we need data depends on what we are using it for, whether that is to provide services to you, for our own legitimate interests (described above) or so that we can comply with the law.

We will actively review the information we hold and when there is no longer a customer, legal or business need for us to hold it, we will either delete it securely or in some cases anonymise it.

Together with our hosting provider, we protect your personal data against unauthorised access, unlawful use, accidental loss, corruption or destruction.

We use technical measures such as **firewalls** , **reverse proxies** , **intrusion detection and prevention** ,   **encryption**  and **password protection**  to protect your data and the systems they are held in. We also use operational measures to protect the data, for example by limiting the number of people who have access to the databases in which our information is held.

We keep these security measures under review and refer to  **industry security standards**  to keep up to date with current best practice.

As a general rule, we do not share your personal data with any other party.

Your IP address, which you use to visit our websites, is shared with our advertising partner, Google AdSense, which we use to display advertising on our forum website. By using our forum website, you explicitly give consent to us for to show you advertising, as we are a not-for-profit organisation, and these ads pay for our hosting requirements.

All data we hold is stored inside the EEA. Your IP may be passed on to Google as part of its AdSense platform.

You are entitled to see copies of all personal data held by us and to amend, correct or delete such data. You can also limit, restrict or object to the processing of your data. You can use do this yourself, using the  **Forum Profile** settings. There are no other locations we hold your data.

You can object to our use of your data where we rely on our legitimate interests to do so. We explained the legitimate interests we rely in the table above under the heading ‘ **How we use your personal data** ’.

To raise any objections or to exercise any of your rights, you can send an email to us at  **data.protection <at>openpli.org**, or contact the webmaster on the forum, via a personal message.

When you get in touch, we will come back to you as soon as possible and where possible within one week. If your request is more complicated, it may take a little longer to come back to you but we will come back to you within a month of your request. There is no charge for most requests, but if you ask us to provide a significant amount of data for example we may ask you to pay a reasonable admin fee. We may also ask you to verify your identity before we provide any information to you.

If we decide to change this privacy policy, the changes will be posted on this page.

← [back to previous]()
